<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE chapter SYSTEM "../../etc/documentation.dtd">
<chapter name="File Formats" id="fileformats">
	<paragraph>
	<phrase edition_le="no">${software} supports a variety of text and image formats ranging
	from plain text over RTF, Microsoft Word and PDF to all image formats provided by the
	operating system and QuickTime.</phrase>
	<phrase edition_pe="no" edition_se="no">${software} supports a variety of text formats
	ranging from plain text over RTF to most Microsoft Word documents.</phrase>Additionally,
	filter services such as AntiWordService enable ${software} and all other service-aware
	applications to read and/or write other file formats.</paragraph>
	<section name="Text Files" id="text">
		<paragraph>${software} supports plain text files (also Mac OS 9 SimpleText and
		Tex-Edit Plus files) in all encodings supported by the operating system including
		Unicode and UTF-8. By default, ${software} automatically recognizes the encoding
		and the line endings used (by Mac, PC or Unix).</paragraph>
		<list>
			<item name="Extensions">aln, applescript, bat, bib, bibtex, c, cls, cmd,
			command, con, cp, cpp, css, csv, em, embl, err, f, f70, f90, fasta, for,
			fpp, gb, genbank, gff, h, hlp, hpp, hs, id2xf, inc, js, lhs, lisp, log,
			lst, m, mi, mis, ml, mly, mm, mmi, mml, msf, p, pas, pir, pl, pp, py, rc,
			scm, scpt, scptd, scriptSuite, scriptTerminology, seq, sh, sqc, sql, ss,
			strings, sty, sw, swiss, tab, tcl, tex, text, txt, v, vcf, wrl, x,
			xchatlog</item>
			<item name="HFS type codes">TEXT, ttro, TERO, sEXT, SimpleText, scpt, osas,
			APPL (AppleScripts wrapped in an executable application)</item>
		</list>
		<note edition_le="no" edition_pe="no">${software} imports tabulated text files and
		vCards such as .tsv, .csv and .vcf as 
		<reference chapter="fileformats" section="sheets">sheets.</reference></note>
		<paragraph>Rich text format: For rich text (RTF), ${software} recognizes Mac, PC
		and ANSI encodings as well as Mac OS X RTF documents with attachments
		(RTFD).</paragraph>
		<list>
			<item name="Extensions">rtf, rtfd</item>
			<item name="HFS type codes">RTF</item>
		</list>
		<paragraph>You can also drag e-mails from Microsoft Entourage (due to a limitation
		in Mac OS X's drag-and-drop system and a proprietary file format used by Microsoft
		currently only one at a time) or selected text to ${software} and store them as RTF
		documents. 
		<phrase edition_le="no" edition_pe="no">For Apple Mail and other e-mail
		applications use the provided 
		<reference chapter="scripts" section="scriptmenuextra">
		scripts.</reference></phrase></paragraph>
	</section>
	<section name="Microsoft Word Files" id="word">
		<paragraph>${software} is also capable of importing native Word documents using the
		conversion mechanism of the operating system. Alternatively, you can use our free 
		<reference chapter="otherproducts" section="freeware">AntiWordService</reference>to
		import Word documents as plain text files.</paragraph>
		<list>
			<item name="Extension">doc</item>
			<item name="HFS type codes">W8BN</item>
		</list>
	</section>
	<section name="Bookmarks &amp; Clippings" id="bookmarks">
		<paragraph>Drag or paste Internet addresses from any Internet application or
		Internet location files from the Finder to ${software} to create special "Link"
		documents consisting of a clickable URL. ${software} is especially optimized to
		accept Safari bookmarks. Also, ${software} stores links to files on your hard disk
		or mounted servers and accepts Mac OS 9 and Mac OS X text clippings as well as
		iChat log files.</paragraph>
		<list>
			<item name="Extensions">clipping, dtLink, ftploc, fileloc, inetloc,
			mailloc, newsloc, textClipping, url, webloc</item>
			<item name="HFS type codes">clpt, ilht, ilft, ilfi, ilma, ilnw, ilaf, ilat,
			ilns, ilge, LINK</item>
		</list>
	</section>
	<section name="Chat Logs" id="chatlogs">
		<paragraph>${software} understands the text format of logs generated by iChat or
		Yahoo Messenger. You can import them like rich text files.</paragraph>
		<list>
			<item name="Extensions">chat, ichat</item>
			<item name="HFS type codes">YMSG</item>
		</list>
	</section>
	<section name="HTML, XML &amp; Co." edition_le="no" id="markup">
		<paragraph>In addition to the text encodings already listed, ${software} supports
		the standard HTML transcriptions for special characters, for example German umlauts
		and French accents. HTML can also be converted to plain text using 
		<reference chapter="menus" section="data">"Data &gt; Convert &gt;
		...".</reference>XML files of any kind can also be imported and are displayed using
		syntax colouring. Preference property lists of Mac OS X 10.4 are binary and are
		converted on-the-fly to readable XML.</paragraph>
		<paragraph>Also, ${software} supports web archives to store HTML pages including
		all necessary images for displaying them offline.</paragraph>
		<list>
			<item name="Extensions">asp, aspx, cgi, cfm, dtd, ent, htm, html, idata,
			jhtml, jsp, mhtml, ompl, ooutline, php, php3, php4, phtml, plist, sgm,
			sgml, shtm, shtml, wml, xbl, xhtm, xhtml, xml, xmloutline, xsl, xslt,
			webarchive</item>
		</list>
	</section>
	<section name="PDF, PostScript" edition_le="no" id="pdf">
		<paragraph>${software} uses the advanced capabilities of Cocoa, thus you can import
		Portable Document Format (PDF) files (and PostScript files) not only as images, but
		also with searchable and analyzable text. By default, ${software} uses Mac OS X's
		PDFKit (on Mac OS X 10.3 Panther the command line tool "pdftotext") to store an
		invisible text-only version of the PDF together with its document. Therefore, it is
		possible to search for single words within PDFs by using 
		<reference chapter="drawers" section="seealso">"See also"</reference>or 
		<reference chapter="drawers" section="seealso">"Classify"</reference>in the text,
		but not the image contents. PostScript files are converted on-the-fly to
		PDF.</paragraph>
		<paragraph edition_le="no">Alternatively, you can use the built-in PDF-to-text
		function to store PDF documents as simple text documents. Choose your options in
		the 
		<reference chapter="preferences">preference panel.</reference></paragraph>
		<note>If either of the options "use built-in PDFtotext" or "Convert to rich text"
		is checked, only text is imported and linked to the PDF file. This is true even if
		"Use PDFKit (Tiger)" is checked.</note>
		<paragraph edition_le="no">You can, later, manually convert imported PDFs to plain
		text or RTF by selecting 
		<reference chapter="menus" section="data">"Data &gt; Convert to Plain Text/Convert
		to Rich Text".</reference>The plain text or RTF version of the PDF appears as a new
		document at the top level of the database.</paragraph>
		<note edition_le="no">It's not yet possible to extract text from protected PDF
		files. Protected PDFs are imported as simple images. You can correctly view the PDF
		in ${software}, though, after entering the correct password.</note>
	</section>
	<section name="Sheet/Record Formats" edition_le="no" edition_pe="no" id="sheets">
		<paragraph>${software} imports various structured file formats and stores their
		contents as sheets and records, e.g. Tab-Separated-Values and
		Comma-Separated-Values (TSV/CSV) and iData2 files. Also, BibTeX files will be
		imported as a sheet in ${software}.</paragraph>
		<list>
			<item name="Extensions">bibtex, csv, idata, tdf, tsv, vcf</item>
		</list>
		<note>Due to limitation in Mac OS X's Cocoa memory management, sheets are currently
		limited to 32767 records.</note>
	</section>
	<section name="Outliner Formats" edition_le="no" edition_pe="no" id="outliner">
		<paragraph>${software} is able to handle outliner files created by OmniOutliner and
		other applications in both OmniOutliner format and OPML (Outlining Processor Markup
		Language). When importing such files, ${software} recreates a groups hierarchy,
		when exporting, it generates one OmniOutliner/OPML file out of multiple groups and
		documents.</paragraph>
		<list>
			<item name="Extensions">outliner, opml</item>
		</list>
	</section>
	<section name="Image Formats" edition_le="no" id="images">
		<paragraph>${software} recognizes all image formats supported by Cocoa, namely BMP,
		Cursors, EPS, Fax, Flashpix, GIF, Icons, JPEG, Mac Paint, PICT, PDF, PNG, Painting,
		Photoshop, Quicktime Image, raw RGB, SGI image format, Targa and TIFF. On Mac OS X
		10.4 or with QuickTime 7 installed, ${software} additionally supports JPEG2000,
		Adobe DNG, OpenEXR and some raw formats.</paragraph>
		<list>
			<item name="Extensions">bmp, cur, eps, fax, fpix, fpx, gif, icns, ico,
			jpeg, jpg, mac, pct, pdf, pict, png, pnt, pntg, psd, qti, qtif, rgb, sgi,
			targa, tga, tif, tiff; Mac OS X 10.4 or QuickTime 7 only: jp2, dng, exr,
			raw</item>
			<item name="HFS type codes">8BPS, BMPf, EPSF, FPix, GIFf, 'ICO ', JPEG,
			'PDF ', PICT, PNGf, PNTG, 'SGI ', TIFF, TPIC, qtif</item>
		</list>
		<paragraph edition_le="no">Note that installed applications or services can add
		support for other file formats to Cocoa and so also to ${software}. The above list
		is the minimum directly supported by Cocoa.</paragraph>
	</section>
	<section name="QuickTime Files" edition_le="no" id="quicktime">
		<paragraph>${software} displays or plays 
		<link href="http://www.apple.com/quicktime">QuickTime</link>movies, sounds and
		Shockwave animations. To add movies, sounds or MP3s to ${software}, import them
		like any other file to your database.</paragraph>
		<paragraph>These files can also be dragged into a rich text document, so that these
		media files can be integrated with text and images in a document.</paragraph>
		<list>
			<item name="Extensions">3g2, 3gp, 3gp2, 3gpp, aac, adts, aif, AIF, aifc,
			AIFC, AIFF, aiff, amc, amr, atr, AU, au, avi, bwf, caf, cdda, cel, dif, dv,
			dvd, flc, fli, gsm, kar, m15, m1a, m1s, m1v, m2a, m3u, m4a, m4b, m4p, m4v,
			m75, mid, midi, mov, MOV, mp2, mp3, MP3, mp4, mpa, mpeg, mpg, mpm, mpv,
			mqv, MQV, pls, qht, qhtm, qt, qtpf, qtz, rtsp, sd2, sdp, sdv, skin, smf,
			smi, smil, sml, SND, snd, swa, swf, ulw, ULW, vfw, wav, WAV</item>
			<item name="HFS type codes">.SMI, .WAV, 3gp2, 3gpp, adts, AIFC, AIFF, ALAW,
			'amc ', 'amr ', attr, caff, cdda, DAVI, DIVX, dvc!, embd, 'FLI ', grip,
			'GSM ', hmov, 'M1A ', 'M1V ', Midi, MooV, 'Mp3 ', 'MP3 ', MPEG, 'MPG ',
			MPG2, MPG3, mpg4, MPGa, MPGA, MPGv, MPGV, MPGx, mxfd, PLAY, qhtm, rtsp,
			Sd2f, 'sdp ', 'sdv ', SMIL, SwaT, SWFL, ULAW, 'VfW ', WAVE</item>
		</list>
	</section>
</chapter>
