<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE chapter SYSTEM "../../etc/documentation.dtd">
<chapter name="Usage Scenarios" id="scenarios">
	<paragraph>An overview about how you can use ${software} for your everyday tasks, from
	surfing the Internet to making notes, cataloging photos and archiving e-mails.</paragraph>
	<section name="Analyzing" id="analyzing" edition_le="no">
		<image src="devonthinkpro/scenario_analyzing.jpg" align="left" scaling="40%"
		edition_le="no" />
		<paragraph>With its built-in A.I. functions, ${software} can be used to analyze
		large amounts of text documents. 
		<phrase edition_pe="no">The 
		<reference chapter="windows" section="concordance">concordance
		function</reference>allows to create a list of all words in a database, sorted by
		its frequency and restricted to a given length.</phrase>The "Search" and "Similar"
		buttons open drawers with all documents containing or words contextually similar to
		the selected word almost instantly. A search toolbar item let's you find any word
		of interest.</paragraph>
		<paragraph>Other functions that help you analyzing documents are the A.I. enhanced 
		<reference chapter="windows" section="search" edition_le="no">search
		function</reference>that also features a similar words list based on spelling or
		contextual similarity as well as the 
		<reference chapter="drawers" section="seealso">"See Also"</reference>button that
		lists documents with a similar content and the topics pop-up menu that displays the
		most important words of a document. Duplicate documents are instantly marked in
		blue and bold, replicants and cross-links help you create a network of
		documents.</paragraph>
		<paragraph>Possible uses:</paragraph>
		<list>
			<item>Analyze the complexity of a given document collection</item>
			<item>Quickly find relations between documents or snippets</item>
			<item>Clean up large document collections at ease</item>
		</list>
	</section>
	<section name="Archiving E-Mails" id="archiving" edition_pe="no" edition_le="no">
		<image src="devonthinkpro/scenario_archiving.jpg" align="left" scaling="60%"
		edition_le="no" />
		<paragraph>${software} is a perfect repository for e-mails you want to keep. Its
		hierarchical groups structure and the automatic classification function are
		perfectly suited to sort in new e-mails and help you finding them again when you
		need them. ${software} comes with a variety of 
		<reference chapter="scripts">AppleScript scripts</reference>that transfer selected
		e-mails or complete mailboxes from Apple Mail, Barebones Mailsmith, Eudora,
		Powermail and Microsoft Entourage. Using the scripts in the 
		<reference chapter="scripts" section="scriptsmenu">Scripts menu,</reference>you can
		even reply to archived e-mails directly from within ${software}.</paragraph>
		<paragraph>Possible uses:</paragraph>
		<list>
			<item>Archive your important correspondence</item>
			<item>Archive invoices, offers, purchases or software licenses</item>
			<item>Store interesting newsbits from newsletters</item>
			<item>Keep project-related e-mails and other documents together</item>
		</list>
	</section>
	<section name="Browsing" id="browsing">
		<image src="devonthinkpro/scenario_browsing.jpg" align="left" scaling="40%"
		edition_le="no" edition_pe="no" />
		<paragraph>Besides being an knowledge and information database, ${software} also
		comes with a 
		<reference chapter="views" section="html">built-in web browser</reference>based on
		Apple's Safari engine that extends the document-based approach to knowledge to the
		world-wide web. Being a database, ${software}'s web browser does not work in a
		window style like Safari or 
		<reference chapter="otherproducts" section="devonagent">DEVONagent,</reference>but
		is document-oriented.</paragraph>
		<paragraph>This enables you as an infoworker to treat web pages the same way like
		you deal with your documents. You simply select a "web document" (bookmark) and
		${software} immediately loads and displays its "content" live from the Internet in
		the view/edit pane. You can then clip contents as plain or rich text documents. 
		<phrase edition_le="no">Also, you can archive the complete page to the database for
		offline viewing.</phrase></paragraph>
		<paragraph edition_le="no" edition_pe="no">Like 
		<reference chapter="otherproducts" section="devonagent">
		DEVONagent,</reference>${software}'s web browser displays 
		<reference chapter="scenarios" section="rss">RSS/RDF/Atom feeds</reference>that
		allows knowledge miners to view frequently used web pages and clip important
		information right away to the database.</paragraph>
		<paragraph>Possible uses:</paragraph>
		<list>
			<item>Visit frequently used websites in a convenient interface</item>
			<item>Integrate "live" content from the web with your other
			documents</item>
			<item>Easily grab data from websites and store it in ${software}</item>
			<item edition_le="no">Capture and archive complete web pages</item>
		</list>
	</section>
	<section name="Cataloging Disks" id="catalogingdisks" edition_le="no">
		<paragraph>By using the 
		<reference chapter="menus" section="file">index and link</reference>functionality,
		${software} can also be used to set up a catalog for CD-ROMs or other removable
		volumes. Create a group for each disk by using the index function, ${software} will
		automatically use links for unknown file types if told so in the preferences. Then,
		organize your disks/groups in any way you like. When you need a specific file,
		search for it in ${software}, insert the volume, control-click the file in
		${software} and select "Launch Path" to open the original file on the removable
		volume.</paragraph>
		<paragraph>Possible uses:</paragraph>
		<list>
			<item>Find files even when they're on a removable volume not currently
			mounted</item>
			<item>Create a virtual library for all your CD-ROMs and other media</item>
			<item>Integrate static documents with other project-related data</item>
		</list>
	</section>
	<section name="Cataloging Photos &amp; MP3s" id="catalogingphotos" edition_le="no">
		<image src="devonthinkpro/scenario_images.jpg" align="left" scaling="40%"
		edition_le="no" edition_pe="no" />
		<paragraph>Besides storing text documents and PDF files, ${software} is also able
		to manage multimedia data such as photos, illustrations, MP3s or movies. While
		never designed to be a iPhoto or iTunes replacements, its a convenient repository
		for images you frequently use or interface to your MP3 library if you don't like
		other music software. Depending on your 
		<reference chapter="preferences" section="import">import
		preferences,</reference>${software} either stores multimedia files in the database
		packages or just links to them. Using the latter, you leave all files where they
		are and simply organize and access them from ${software}.</paragraph>
		<paragraph>Possible uses:</paragraph>
		<list>
			<item>Create a database only for photos</item>
			<item>View your images in full screen mode</item>
			<item>Keep project-related images and other documents together</item>
			<item>Play your MP3s from within your work environment</item>
		</list>
	</section>
	<section name="Collecting Snippets" id="snippets">
		<image src="devonthinkpro/scenario_snippets.jpg" align="left" scaling="40%"
		edition_le="no" edition_pe="no" />
		<paragraph>Using Mac OS X's very handy 
		<reference chapter="menus" section="services">"Services"
		menu,</reference>${software} is the #1 tool for collecting and organizing
		information bits and snippets on the Mac. Simply select any piece of data you think
		that could be useful and capture it to the currently open database with a keystroke
		or a short visit to the "Services" menu. All Cocoa applications (such as TextEdit,
		Safari or ${software} itself) as well as many new Carbon applications (e.h. the
		Finder or Microsoft Office 2004) support this mechanism.</paragraph>
		<paragraph>${software} automatically sets the title of the newly created snippet to
		the first line of text, so there's a good chance that you don't even need to rename
		it. New snippets are either created in the top level of the database or any group
		you name in the preferences. 
		<phrase edition_le="no">Also, ${software} can automatically classify and file them
		by using its built-in artificial intelligence.</phrase></paragraph>
		<note>Use our freeware tool 
		<reference chapter="otherproducts" section="freeware">HotService</reference>to move
		the "Services" submenu to the top level of the menu bar.</note>
		<paragraph>Possible uses:</paragraph>
		<list>
			<item>Collect recent news from your favorite web sites</item>
			<item>Keep important information from any source and your other
			project-related documents together</item>
			<item>Quickly create an info collection for a specific topic</item>
		</list>
	</section>
	<section name="Indexing Files" id="indexing" edition_le="no">
		<paragraph>Besides completely importing documents, ${software} can simply index
		files. This way, ${software} reads the contents of the file and stores it for
		internal reference, but it always uses the external file for displaying the actual
		contents. Use indexing for easily accessing information stored in CD-ROMs, creating
		a library of all important documents regardless where they are physically stored or
		integrating files stored elsewhere with your documents in ${software}. Indexed
		files appear with a little book symbol in front of their icons and can be updated
		manually with the 
		<reference chapter="menus" section="file">"Synchronize"
		function.</reference></paragraph>
		<note>A future version of ${software} will keep indexed files up-to-date
		automatically and allow editing of indexed files.</note>
		<paragraph>Possible uses:</paragraph>
		<list>
			<item>Quickly access information from CD-ROMs</item>
			<item>Create a front-end for your document collection</item>
			<item>Integrate static documents with other project-related data</item>
		</list>
	</section>
	<section name="Managing Bookmarks" id="bookmarks">
		<image src="devonthinkpro/scenario_bookmarks.jpg" align="left" scaling="60%"
		edition_le="no" edition_pe="no" />
		<paragraph>With its integrated document-based 
		<reference chapter="views" section="html">web browser,</reference>${software} is an
		excellent bookmark manager. Organize all your bookmarks as link documents and visit
		any website by simply selecting it in the hierarchy list. ${software} automatically
		loads the page and displays it in the view/edit pane. And if you want to open it in
		your default browser, e.g. Firefox or Safari, simply control-click it and select
		"Launch URL" from the contextual menu.</paragraph>
		<paragraph>Possible uses:</paragraph>
		<list>
			<item>Manage your bookmarks</item>
			<item>Keep project-related websites and other documents together</item>
			<item>Visit frequently used websites in a convenient interface</item>
			<item>Integrate "live" content from the web with your other
			documents</item>
			<item>Easily grab data from websites and store it in ${software}</item>
		</list>
	</section>
	<section name="Reading Newsfeeds" id="rss" edition_le="no" edition_pe="no">
		<image src="devonthinkpro/scenario_rss.jpg" align="left" scaling="60%"
		edition_le="no" edition_pe="no" />
		<paragraph>${software}'s integrated 
		<reference chapter="views" section="html">web browser</reference>fully supports RSS
		newsfeeds which, together with the possibility to 
		<reference chapter="scenarios" section="bookmarks">organize
		bookmarks</reference>like documents, makes it a convenient, comfortable newsreader.
		Create a group with all the newsfeeds you visit regularly, view them with just one
		click and clip the most important data with just a few clicks.</paragraph>
		<paragraph>Possible uses:</paragraph>
		<list>
			<item>Read your daily news in a convenient interface</item>
			<item>Integrate "live" newsfeeds with your other documents</item>
			<item>Easily grab interesting information and store it in
			${software}</item>
		</list>
	</section>
	<section name="Taking Notes" id="notes">
		<image src="devonthinkpro/menu_dock.jpg" align="left" scaling="40%" edition_le="no"
		edition_pe="no" />
		<paragraph>${software} is perfectly suited for taking notes and organizing them.
		Use ${software}'s 
		<reference chapter="menus" section="dock">Dock menu</reference>to quickly create
		new notes, write them with all the advances text editing capabilities of Mac OS X
		and find a place to file them in your groups hierarchy using the "Classify"
		button.</paragraph>
		<paragraph>Possible uses:</paragraph>
		<list>
			<item>Write down ideas before they vanish</item>
			<item>Conveniently take phone messages</item>
			<item>Keep project notes and your other project-related documents
			together</item>
		</list>
	</section>
	<section name="Writing &amp; Outlining" id="writing">
		<image src="devonthinkpro/scenario_writing.jpg" align="left" scaling="40%"
		edition_le="no" edition_pe="no" />
		<paragraph>With its hierarchical group structure, organization and navigation
		functions as well as its advanced text editing capabilities based on the Mac OS X
		text engine 
		<phrase edition_le="no" edition_pe="no">and the full screen
		mode,</phrase>${software} is perfectly suited for writing text from notes to whole
		books. Create new documents with just one click, find 
		<reference chapter="drawers" section="seealso">related documents</reference>and
		network them with Wiki-style or static cross-links. Because ${software} is a
		database, you can switch from one document to another with just one click and
		manage even larger projects at ease.</paragraph>
		<paragraph>Also, by making groups and documents checkable, ${software} can also be
		used as a very simple outliner. Unlike other outliners, ${software} uses documents
		as items and groups for items that have sub-items. Use it with the 
		<reference chapter="windows" section="main">"Horizontal Split" view</reference>to
		create an outliner look-and-feel.</paragraph>
		<paragraph>Possible uses:</paragraph>
		<list>
			<item>Write notes, white papers, letters</item>
			<item>Write book chapters and organize them</item>
			<item>Organize your ideas or projects in outlines</item>
			<item>Create a network of information for your projects or interests</item>
		</list>
	</section>
</chapter>
