<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE chapter SYSTEM "../etc/documentation.dtd">
<chapter name="Other Products" id="otherproducts">
	<paragraph>Besides ${software}, DEVONtechnologies publishes a number of other commercial,
	shareware, and freeware applications, and services that you may be interested
	in.</paragraph>
	<section name="At a Glance" id="intro">
		<paragraph>DEVONtechnologies is focused on developing innovative applications for
		finding, storing, and organizing information. Our main objective is to make complex
		yet flexible technology that is both easy to use and lightning fast.</paragraph>
		<list>
			<item>
				<reference chapter="otherproducts" section="devonthink">
				DEVONthink</reference>
			</item>
			<item>
				<reference chapter="otherproducts" section="devonagent">
				DEVONagent</reference>
			</item>
			<item>
				<reference chapter="otherproducts" section="devonnote">
				DEVONnote</reference>
			</item>
		</list>
		<paragraph>All applications are based on the DEVONtechnology, a powerful and solid
		core unique to DEVONtechnologies. DEVONthink, DEVONnote, and DEVONagent are only
		the first of many more DEVONtechnology-applications yet to come.</paragraph>
		<subsection name="Newsletter &amp; Forum">
			<paragraph>Would you like DEVONtechnologies to keep you informed about
			updates and new product releases? 
			<link href="http://www.devon-technologies.com/news/newsletter.php">
			Subscribe to the newsletter.</link></paragraph>
			<paragraph>And don't forget to have a look at our very lively 
			<link href="http://www.devon-technologies.com/support/forum.html">user
			forum</link>, where users of all skill levels meet to discuss our
			applications, talk about our technology, and exchange tips and tricks for
			DEVONthink &amp; Co.</paragraph>
		</subsection>
	</section>
	<section name="DEVONthink" id="devonthink">
		<subsection name="The Real Paperless Office">
			<paragraph>Make the dream of the paperless office come true with DEVONthink
			and keep all your text and RTF files, scanned documents, notes, emails,
			images, chat logs, bookmarks, and multimedia files together in one simple
			to use database. 
			<!-- NOTE: Using a bulleted list in the middle of a sentence is grammatically clunky; consider using a regular sentence, with the terms previously highlighted with bullets (such as text and RTF files, scanned documents, etc.) bolded for effect. -->DEVONthink
			allows you to integrate both local documents and live content from the
			Internet, keeping all project- related information stored in one
			easy-to-access place.</paragraph>
		</subsection>
		<subsection name="Why DEVONthink?">
			<paragraph>DEVONthink not only stores documents, it also facilitates
			editing, analyzing, organizing, finding, and archiving your documents with
			its flexible work environment, powerful organization tools, and built-in AI
			architecture.</paragraph>
			<!-- Again, bulleted list is really clunky; better to use sentence with bolded terms ('editing,' 'analyzing,' 'organizing,' 'finding' and 'archiving,' in this case) -->
		</subsection>
		<subsection name="Integrated Workspace">
			<paragraph>Unlike Mac OS X's Finder, DEVONthink provides an integrated work
			environment with all the tools you need for working with information of all
			kinds, from simple text to PDFs and multimedia files. DEVONthink can
			intelligently assist you with filing documents, finding similar files, or
			searching the database, saving you the trouble of having to manually manage
			thousands of files.</paragraph>
			<paragraph>As a native Mac application, DEVONthink is also tightly
			integrated with the Mac OS X operating system and its frameworks. It
			provides a dock menu, Services menu commands, and even makes heavy use of
			the Safari web browser engine and Mac OS X 10.4 Tiger's advanced PDF
			library.</paragraph>
		</subsection>
		<paragraph>
			<link href="http://www.devon-technologies.com/products/devonthink">Click
			here to read more about DEVONthink.</link>
		</paragraph>
	</section>
	<section name="DEVONagent" id="devonagent">
		<paragraph>DEVONagent overcomes all the shortcomings that make Google &amp; Co.
		such a pain to use for serious research projects. With more than 130 plug-ins for
		popular search engines, DEVONagent has scientific databases and research tools, and
		predefined search sets that you can use right away with amazing results. The
		application also has a clean, easy-to-use user interface. All this and more make
		DEVONagent the number one tool for finding information on the web with a
		Mac.</paragraph>
		<paragraph name="Why DEVONagent">DEVONagent is much more than just an interface for
		web search engines; it helps you find, collect, and organize information with a
		powerful and flexible search architecture. It also has a simple to use built-in
		archive, and tight integration with DEVONthink. 
		<!-- Bulleted lists mid-sentence not best option grammatically; consider using sentence with elements 'find,' 'collect,' and 'organize' bolded for emphasis. -->DEVONagent
		creates summaries, acts as a fast and lean web browser, and shows all items of
		interest in a separate drawer. DEVONagent is the easiest way to look for
		information on the web. 
		<!-- If previous statement is too strong, consider changing to "We think DEVONagent is the easiest way to look for information on the web." Best to use a positive, bold statement. --></paragraph>
		<paragraph name="DEVONthink Companion">DEVONagent is the perfect extension to your
		DEVONthink database. With DEVONagent you can save found information directly to
		your database as plain or rich text, as a web archive, or as a PDF-all with a
		single click of your mouse. You can then use DEVONthink's intelligence to organize
		this newly collected data conveniently and quickly.</paragraph>
		<paragraph name="What You Can Use It For">There are many different ways to use
		DEVONagent and to integrate it into your workflow. Some examples
		include:</paragraph>
		<list>
			<item>Journalists, who use ${software} to collect hot news, and who use
			copy-and-paste to transfer the summary to the word processing program of
			their choice. "See also" and DEVONagent's intelligent filters also help
			journalists eliminate junk information and/or duplicate or irrelevant pages
			on-the-fly.</item>
			<item>Analysts, who need to stay up-to-date with everything that happens in
			their industry. With DEVONagent they define their own search sets that
			return exactly what they're interested in, storing the key information in
			the integrated archive.</item>
			<item>Scientists and students, who directly access specialized databases,
			scan important websites, and receive relevant news via RSS. These users
			then transfer the most interesting articles as web archive, plain text,
			RTF, or PDF files into DEVONthink with a single click of the mouse.</item>
			<item>Lawyers, who wish to stay up-to-date with new laws, precendence
			setting cases and interpretations, and with their main clients.
			DEVONagent's scheduler does this automatically, letting the lawyers
			concentrate on their work, instead of searching the web for
			information.</item>
			<item>Home users, who are interested in genealogical research, finding
			desktop pictures, searching for long-lost friends, or simply using
			DEVONagent as a high-end interface for Google and MSN Search.</item>
		</list>
		<paragraph>
			<link href="http://www.devon-technologies.com/products/devonagent">Click
			here to read more about DEVONagent.</link>
		</paragraph>
	</section>
	<section name="DEVONnote" id="devonnote">
		<subsection name="Organize Your Thoughts">
			<paragraph>DEVONnote helps you take notes and keep them organized. It keeps
			all your ideas, documents, important information, and even your web
			browser's bookmarks in one single, accessible place. DEVONnote supports you
			with professional, easy-to-use features, and helps create structure out of
			chaos.</paragraph>
			<!-- Consider adding mention of how DEVONnote helps create structure out of chaos; example: "...and helps create structure out of chaos with its unique filing system." -->
			<paragraph>DEVONnote is the most sophisticated notepad application for Mac
			OS X, and the only one that uses AI (artificial intelligence) instead of
			relying on your NI (natural intelligence).</paragraph>
			<!-- Consider adding a line about why AI is preferred to NI in this context; as it reads now, the sentence seems to say that AI is preferrable to NI because the user is not very intelligent (at least, not intelligent enough to rely on their NI). -->
		</subsection>
		<subsection name="Why DEVONnote?">
			<paragraph>DEVONnote was designed with the typical Mac user in mind-a user
			who is:</paragraph>
			<list>
				<item>Creative</item>
				<item>Professional (whether at work or at home)</item>
				<!-- "Professional" in the U.S. often connotates business, or work only, and is not usually associated with activities done at home or for hobbists/students; consider alternative word choice, such as "practical," "knowledgable," or "savvy"—these words will cover business people as well as home users, students, etc. -->
				<item>Desiring quality software</item>
			</list>
			<paragraph>Consequently, DEVONnote comes with a clean, easy-to-use
			interface that gives you all the tools you need in a familiar Mac-like
			package. Even the most complex AI functions are just »buttons«, meaning one
			simple click can send DEVONnote into action, digging through all of your
			data to find a place for your latest note, or to show you all your ideas
			and concepts that are similar to the one you've just selected.</paragraph>
		</subsection>
		<subsection name="Brain Food Included">
			<paragraph>Of course, creative people don't just »have thoughts«, they
			often need new »input«, too. 
			<!-- Consider using the word "inspiration" instead of "input," as input seems a little too computerese/sterile -->We
			understand that, and that's the reason why DEVONnote comes with a complete
			Safari-based web browser and solid, but flexible, bookmark-managing
			capabilities. With DEVONnote, you can browse your favourite websites, then
			clip and save the most important information directly to your DEVONnote
			notebook.</paragraph>
			<paragraph>But, of course, life is not just work! Use DEVONnote to watch
			and organize your favorite cams, directly within your notepad.</paragraph>
			<!-- Not sure what you mean by "cams" - if meaning webcam, be sure to say webcam for clarity. Also, try for consistency with "webcam"— in this document, it is one word, however on your website it is two: web cam. Best to pick one and use exclusively. I recommend using the single word. -->
		</subsection>
		<paragraph>
			<link href="http://www.devon-technologies.com/products/devonnote">Click
			here to read more about DEVONnote.</link>
		</paragraph>
	</section>
	<section name="PhotoStickies" id="photostickies">
		<subsection name="">
			<paragraph>PhotoStickies displays one or more photos (located on your local
			drives or on the Internet) on your screen. It also shows webcam pictures,
			acts as a fast image viewer, and records and replays slideshows.
			PhotoStickies can even be used as a wallpaper utility.</paragraph>
			<paragraph>In contrast to other "sticky" solutions, all of PhotoStickies'
			windows are borderless, and may float above or behind other application or
			Finder windows directly on your desktop. As PhotoStickies supports (and
			even calculates) alpha channels and transparency, your stickies and
			background images don't have to be opaque rectangles. And, if you don't
			want your photos to be in your way, let the clicks go right through them as
			if they weren't even there.</paragraph>
			<paragraph>Additional features include real-time filtering (like blur,
			sharpen, adjust contrast and brightness, etc.) of images, webcams and
			slideshows to improve display quality, and a special webcam mode that can
			save your bandwidth for other tasks so you may monitor many different
			webcams at the same time. PhotoStickies has the ability to revert to saved
			states on startup, includes favorites, and even zooming, rotating, tiling
			and flipping of images. The application can be run as a menu extra, is
			highly multi-threaded, supports multiple screens, drag-and-drop, contextual
			menus, a dock menu, a processes panel, and a inspector panel. It
			understands all image formats provided by Cocoa, such as PDF, EPS, PICT,
			TIFF, JPEG, Photoshop (PSD), or icons (ICNS, ICO).</paragraph>
		</subsection>
		<subsection name="Key Features">
			<list>
				<item>Displays local images or webcam pictures on your
				desktop</item>
				<item>Records webcams over a period of time, ideal for surveillance
				cams</item>
				<item>Can be used as a ultra-fast image viewer</item>
				<item>Filters images for better image quality</item>
				<item>Server-based list with new webcams; users can post new cams
				to the server</item>
				<item>Built to seamlessly integrate with Mac OS X</item>
			</list>
		</subsection>
		<subsection name="What's Unique">
			<list>
				<item>Uses all Quartz image features such as alpha channels and
				transparency</item>
				<item>Comes with real-time image filters</item>
				<item>Images can be shown frameless</item>
				<item>Can be run as a Menu Extra</item>
				<item>Understands all Quartz and QuickTime image formats</item>
				<item>Built to seamlessly integrate with Mac OS X</item>
			</list>
		</subsection>
		<paragraph>
			<link href="http://www.devon-technologies.com/products/shareware">Click
			here to read more about PhotoStickies.</link>
		</paragraph>
	</section>
	<section name="Needful Things" id="freeware">
		<subsection name="EasyFind">
			<paragraph>As an alternative to-or supplement of-Sherlock, EasyFind finds
			files, folders, or contents in any file without the need for indexing. This
			is especially useful if you are tired of slow or impossible indexing,
			outdated or corrupted indices, or if you are just looking for missing
			features like case sensitive or insensitive search, Boolean operators,
			wildcards, or searching for phrases. In addition, EasyFind uses
			multi-threading and is therefore very responsive, even with multiple search
			processes running. 
			<!-- "multi-threading" is hyphenated here to be consistent with "mutli-threaded," as found in PhotoStickies text above -->The
			application provides contextual menus and Mac OS X Services, and displays
			the location of each item in a separate column for a better overview.
			EasyFind uses little memory, supports drag-and-drop and the clipboard, and
			optionally finds invisible items or items within packages.</paragraph>
		</subsection>
		<subsection name="ThumbsUp">
			<paragraph>ThumbsUp is a simple, drag-and-drop based utility designed to
			create thumbnail images from batches of pictures. (The application supports
			all Mac OS X and QuickTime image formats, including PDF documents.) Image
			size, quality, sharpening, and antialiasing are configurable, and images
			can be scaled by percentage or limited to a maximum size. With a scaling of
			100 percent, ThumbsUp may be used as an ultra-fast, comfortable image
			converter.</paragraph>
			<note>This utility is not intended to be an HTML thumbnail gallery
			generator; there are already lots of them out there.</note>
			<!-- Consider replacing with what the utility *is* intended to be used for instead to emphasis why someone would want to download the application; giving potential users project ideas (such as "use ThumbsUp to create contact sheets, etc.") will draw interest from people who may not otherwise realize how useful the application can be. -->
		</subsection>
		<subsection name="XMenu">
			<paragraph>XMenu brings back the Apple menu to Mac OS X. 
			<!-- Consider rephrasing this sentence for clarity; the Apple menu still exists in OS X, it's just not the same as OS 9's Apple menu. Consider saying something like: "XMenu brings Mac OS 9's Apple menu back from the dead, adding its functionality to Mac OS X." -->The
			application also includes a complete application launcher. By adding one or
			more global menus to the right side of the menu bar, you can easily access
			your preferred applications, folders (and subfolders), documents, and
			files. Furthermore, there's no explicit need for a configuration (like
			creating lots of folders and aliases or adding items to user-defined
			setups)-just activate the menus you like: Applications, Developer
			Applications, Home, Documents, or User-Defined (like the old Apple menu
			found in Mac OS 9).</paragraph>
		</subsection>
		<subsection name="Freeware Services">
			<paragraph>Besides the full-blown freeware applications, DEVONtechnologies
			also offers a variety of useful services that extend the functionality of
			Mac OS X's Services menu and that allow Cocoa applications like TextEdit or
			DEVONthink to open Microsoft Word documents as plain text files, or PDFs as
			RTF files. These services include:</paragraph>
			<list>
				<item>AntiWordService</item>
				<item>BlueService</item>
				<item>CalcService</item>
				<item>HotService</item>
				<item>PDF2RTFService</item>
				<item>WordService</item>
			</list>
			<paragraph>Also, HotService installs a second Services menu right in the
			top level of the menu bar, next to the Window menu. Note: This Services
			menu is only visible in true Cocoa applications such as TextEdit, Mail, or
			DEVONtechnologies' applications.</paragraph>
		</subsection>
		<paragraph>
			<link href="http://www.devon-technologies.com/products/freeware">Click here
			to read more about DEVONtechnologies' freeware applications and
			services.</link>
		</paragraph>
	</section>
</chapter>
